Morris C. McEldowney Military Service in East Asia Photograph Album, 1954-1955 RL.10981
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photograph Album
  - 134: Easter (Box 1)
    Hardly visible is the Easter cross down left center. Crowd is breaking up and departing from the mountain.
  - 135: Easter Sunrise, April 10, 1955 (Box 1)
    Right to left: Durden (Dovie), McCracken (Mac), McE (me), Woods (John), Blank (don't know). Vice Dres. Of Korea (State national (??) guard in rear.
  - 136: Easter Sunrise: Color Guard (Box 1)
    Right to left: US flag, UN flag, Korean, Christian
  - 137: Ko sisters at Easter Sunrise Service (Box 1)
  - 138: Ko Sisters (Box 1)
    Koko (L), Kozie (R )
  - 139: Memorial Day Ceremonies at 8A FWD memorial to Korean War US soldiers (Box 1)
    Monument is located at North Gate Main Post. At R. is General Ferrenbaugh
  - 140: Memorial Day at Korean Soldier Monument on Han River (Box 1)
    Front center: Ferrenbaugh, Front R facing monument: Ambassador Lacey. 3rd row - civilian is Karl Strum, US charge d'affairs. Next: Col. Ed Wilson, our roommate.
  - 141: Pusan Harbor, June 17, 1955 (Box 1)
    Part of Pusan -- area nearest Japan-- has the best shipping facilities in Korea. (F???) was the site of America's last-ditch stand before our invasion at Incheon.
  - 142: Pusan Harbor, June 17, 1955 (Box 1)
    Another view from same location on a hill above the PX.
  - 143: North: Sign reads "Southern limit demilitarized zone: Do not enter", June 15, 1955 (Box 1)
    Taken on Wednesday during my visit as escort for Ken Fristoe at OP site overlooking DMZ.
  - 144: South - Beach at Pusan (Box 1)
    Waiting for my plane on Friday. Herschel Ineeder and I wandered to beach near K-9. Water here is the Yellow Sea and direction is toward the China Coast.
  - 145: L to R; Ch. Schlieser, 2 officers (one is Reg. Commander), Ch. Fristoe, Ch. Redford, June 15, 1955 (Box 1)
    Party stands on height overlooking the Imjin River and the DMZ as shown on reverse.
  - 146: Imjin River and DMZ country (Box 1)
    Freedom Bridge lies between the 2 ink dots on river bank. Below at base of mountain is US civil camp and a dust spangled road leading from river. Korean civilians are not permitted N of Imjin.
  - 147: Looking North into the Commie Territory from US observation post (Box 1)
    Note line of pen marks on photo. Hardly visible above each dot is a white panel marker indicating Southern boundary or DMZ 3 miles beyond are red flags.
  - 148: Rice Paddy (Box 1)
    Preparation of paddy for the planting of rice. This is just plain mud. Can you imagine conducting a war through this kind of terrain? No place for fox holes.
  - 149: Sendai (Box 1)
    This is taken from the chaplain's office in Camp Shimmelpfennig. 1st Cav Div HQ. The rotary in front of N building was simply loaded with color. Flowers of all shapes and hues.
  - 150: Sendai, May 24, 1955 (Box 1)
    This picture was taken from near the same spot as the one on reverse. This is the 1st Cav Div chapel in Shim. Road and walk in foreground lead to the chaplain's office.
  - 151: Southern Baptist Mission Compound, Sendai (Box 1)
    Showing front entrance, maids quarters to R and to R beyond the separate maids quarters, the garage. Foreground: board fence which encloses compound. Maid Ishii San is (???), has a husband - a tailor- and 4 children. All live in 3 rooms.
  - 152: House - showing the terrace (Box 1)
    French doors slide open. At L is a fish pond with fish. Not in picture at L is a fence and the electric power relay station.
  - 153: House - from terrace looking toward street (Box 1)
    Street car passing in distance. Direction is toward town of Sendu -- hospital, camp Sendai, Camp Shim.
  - 154: House interior from terrace (Box 1)
    Living room. Ch. Cooper in chair. Mirror over fireplace reflects the street forest of beams to my rear which is the view from living room and living room French doors. Curtains are installed-- maybe cerise in color -- covering doors.
  - 155: Bridge (Box 1)
  - 156: Bridge (Box 1)
  - 157: Shinto Shrine, Tokyo (Box 1)
    This is the Japanese counterpart to the church or cathedral. Note the variety of gables in this picture and the one on back.
  - 158: Shinto Shrine, Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    Some kind of ceremony was taking place inside this building but I didn't try to go in. The temple was surrounded by flowers and gardens and fountains.
  - 159: Ginza - Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    Tokyo has no sky scrapers although it's the 3rd largest city in the world. Reason: the frequent earthquakes.
  - 160: McEldowney, March 1955 (Box 1)
    En route to my office. Office bldg. at L of picture with the smaller building housing latrine facilities. Am facing toward Faith Hall and S Post.
  - 161: Monument in Hibiya Park, Palace Grounds Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    Horse is particularly good -- mounted warrior in armor. Picture at left was taken against Sun - I tried for silhouette.
  - 162: Imperial Palace, Tokyo, Entrance, March 1955 (Box 1)
    This was one of several entrances. Most of them were closed. This is the only one which seemed to be in use.
  - 163: Liberty Bell, Hibya Park, Tokyo (Box 1)
    This bell is an exact replica of the liberty bell in Philadelphia. It stands on a knoll in the park overlooking the tennis courts. It is nearly hidden and I discovered it by accident.
  - 164: Monument, Imperial Palace, Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    Some severe looking person whose identity I could not learn, and whose features were so weathered and black even my camera failed to record. Probably an emperor.
  - 165: Imperial Palace, Tokyo (Box 1)
    This is one of the entrances to the palace.
  - 166: Plaza in font of Imperial Palace in Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    There were hundreds of tourists, particularly school children, surrounding this plaza.
  - 167: Fountain in Hibya Park, Tokyo (Box 1)
    Rather an unusual picture. Should have had more light. The fountain was an attractive spot right in the center of Hibya Park in downtown Tokyo.
  - 168: Lion at entrance of Shinto Shrine, Tokyo. Monument near the Imperial Palace, Tokyo., March 1955 (Box 1)
  - 169: Hibya Park, Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    This is not far from the famed Imperial Hotel and adjacent to the Imperial Palace. It has beauty as you can see from this lagoon and fountain.
  - 170: Hibya Park, Tokyo, March 1955 (Box 1)
    I was able to crowd a great deal into this picture. I fact there is much more in his picture than there is in the park. I was quite mystified when the picture came from the developer until I discovered that it is a double exposure.
  - 171: Stone turtle at base of pillar (Box 1)
  - 172: Stone turtle at base of monument (Box 1)
  - 174: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)
  - 175: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)
  - 173: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)
  - 176: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)
  - 177: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)
  - 178: Japanese woodblock print (Box 1)